Current Objective

Senior engineer with around 8 years of experience in software engineering for apple platforms now trying to find an interesting and different role. Some areas of interest are Sales consulting and machine learning with deep neural networks.

Work Experience

Ebay Inc.

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

June 2016 - Present

Senior iOS Engineer

- Lead Developer for the 2dehands.be App
- Part of the global team building classified apps for 11 different countries

Layar BV

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

November 2014 - May 2016

Senior iOS Engineer

- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar App
- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar SDK
- Part of the team building the Blippar App and also helping out with Computer Vision tasks

IceMobile Agency BV

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior iOS Engineer

February 2014 - November 2014

- Senior engineer in the iOS development team building apps for the leading supermarkets in the Netherlands such as Jumbo and Albert Heijn
- Gathering business requirements and coming up with efficient technical solutions to address them
- Automating user interface testing and setting up continuous integration

Ebuddy BV iOS Developer Amsterdam, The Netherlands

June 2013 - January 2014

- Working in the iOS Development Team and doing all necessary tasks in order to help build quality iOS Apps.
 - * XMS One of the world's leading social messaging apps

Simple Apps LLC

New Delhi, India

Founder

February 2012 - June 2013

- Building a cluster of interconnected apps to give people a unique user experience on their mobile devices
 - * RedditNode An app for browsing reddit
 - * HackerNode An app for browsing hacker news
 - * DictionaryNode An offline english dictionary app

Self Employed iOS Consultant

New Delhi, India

May 2012 - June 2013

- Helping various companies around the world with their iOS development and design
 - * Beachfront Builder SDK Platform to enable developers to create video feed apps with ease
 - * BeachfrontIO Ad SDK Ad platform to enable developers to monetize their apps with video ads
 - * RosterReminder An app reminding pilots about their flights
 - * Drink Two A drinking game board app
 - * Jamjoc A music sharing app

MicroStrategy Inc. McLean, VA Software Engineer September 2010 - January 2012

- Worked on several iOS Development projects and helped automate various tasks

- * Usher An app for managing events
- * Alert An app for interacting with customers through facebook
- * MicroStrategy Mobile SDK A higher level SDK for making MicroStrategy Apps

Citisync.com iOS Developer

Gainesville,FL

January 2010- July 2010

- Helped Citisync.com build their iPhone Application

- * Built the iPhone application. Unfortunately the app is not live anymore.
- * Also wrote some server side scripts for generating xml PHP

University of Florida, Department of Emergency Medicine

Gainesville,FL

Java Developer

September 2009 - February 2010

- Together with the resident doctors, developed a board game with Java Swing that helped medical students learn in an interactive manner

Bloomberg LP

New York, NY

Financial Software Development Intern

May 2009 - August 2009

- As an intern I helped out with a number of projects in the Global Trading team
 - * Created Bloomberg function GTRE for managing email recipient lists Javascript, C++
 - * Added some new features to a few backend services C++

Education

University of Florida

Gaineville,FL

Masters in Computer Engineering

August 2008 - August 2010

- CGPA: 3.6/4.0 (Click here to View Grades)

Skills

Languages: Objective C, Swift, C, C++, Python, Bash

Technical Skills: Scalable software engineering, Machine learning, Deep Neural networks.

Business Skills: Gathering requirements from clients, Communicating technical difficulties and possibilities in a simple manner, Converting business goals into technical requirements, Managing expectations, Aligning with business goals.

Other Interests

Flying small planes, Hiking, Bouldering, Travel, Latin Dancing, Poker, Billiards.